# Mahdi Gharooni

### **Flutter Developer**

**Mobile:** (+98) 9120262947 **E-mail:** <u>mmahdi.gjafari69@gmail.com</u>

GitHub: https://github.com/MahdiGharooni/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahdigharooni/

#### **SUMMARY**

Skilled Mobile Developer with over 4 years of experience in Mobile Programming, including 3 years in Flutter, and 1 year in Android development. Familiar with Mobile Native Languages (Java, Swift) and eager to learn more. Have mainly focused on building cross-platform applications with various features and contributing to open-source projects.

#### **SKILLS**

Flutter, Dart, OOP, Design Patterns, WebSocket, Firebase, SQLite, Git, CI/CD, Unit Testing, TDD Agile, Scrum, Teamwork, Creativity
Familiar with: Java, Kotlin, Swift, JavaScript

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Pardakht Novin**, Tehran — Flutter Developer

7/2020 - PRESENT

Pardakht Novin is currently active in the field of electronic payment as one of the companies licensed by the Iran Central Bank.

- Publishing a cross-platform application by Flutter for Android, IOS and web platforms.
- Responsible for refactoring application architecture by Repository Pattern and BloC, making it faster, more testable and legible.
- Developing new features through Java, Swift and JavaScript using Platform Channels and growing 5%
- Debugging and uploading IOS version, lead to attracting over 5k new users.

## **Livecart**, London (part time-remote) — Flutter Developer

8/2021 - PRESENT

Livecart is an innovative eCommerce platform, providing the most convenient local shopping experience, with the power to find, search and explore the nearest local offers.

- Implementing more than 70% of the wrapper by InAppFlutter WebView for Android and IOS platforms.
- Communicating between Flutter and JavaScript with a 50% growth in app efficiency.
- Programming Firebase services like Notifications, Analytics Crashlytics.

## **Tarafdari,** Tehran — Flutter Developer

1/2019 - 6/2020

Tarafdari is the first and most popular sports social media network with millions of users in Iran, providing official news and live scores of national and international matches.

- Publishing a sports news application for Android and IOS platforms by Flutter with over 50k users.
- Developed several features using file-manager, charts and tables, led to attracting 20k new users.
- Implementing TV sport matches streaming with Live Chat on the Socket IO.

## **PROJECTS**

# Flutter Docker Image — GitHub

2/2020

- Uploading a Docker Image to use Flutter commands.
- Helping people to set up CI/CD, with over 400 downloads.

# Idehshop — GitHub

5/2021

- Programming a location-based application by Flutter to display the nearest stores for users with online shopping, leading to 50% time-saving.
- Helping sellers to register their stores and 10 to 30% increase in the number of sales.

## **EDUCATION**

Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University, Tehran

2015 - 2019

**B.Sc. Software Engineering** 

## **LANGUAGES**

Persian: Native English: Fluent